# **Erol Bicer, Ph.D.**Nuclear Engineer



- +82-10-7497-0705
- erolbicer@live.com
- www.erolbicer.com
- nucerl
- South Korea
- **#** 1989/09/29

# **LANGUAGES**

English — Fluent

Turkish — Fluent

Korean — Conversational

## **SYSTEM CODES**

RELAP5 | MARS-KS | SPACE

# **CONTAINMENT CODES**

GOTHIC | CAP

SEVERE ACCIDENT

**MELCOR** 

## **CFD CODES**

OpenFOAM | CUPID

# **CODING LANGUAGES**

MATLAB | FORTRAN | C++ | HTML/CSS | PYTHON

### **TOOLS**

Git | DOS/UNIX | ParaView | Salome | Origin | CATIA | Mathcad | PCTRAN | SNAP

## **PROFILE**

I specialize in conducting comprehensive safety analyses for various types of nuclear power plants using advanced system and computational fluid dynamics codes. My experience encompasses successfully developing, leading, and completing international projects through effective collaboration with global teams.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FNC Technology Co., Ltd. 🛮

Manager

2023 - present | South Korea

Associate Manager

2019 - 2023 | South Korea

Assistant Manager

2016 - 2019 | South Korea

**Bil-Plas Industry and Trade Co., Ltd.,** R&D Engineer ☑ 2013 – 2014 | Ankara, Turkey

# **EDUCATION**

**Nuclear Engineering, Ph.D.,** Seoul National University 

2024 | Seoul, South Korea

Nuclear Power Plant Engineering, M.Sc., KINGS ☑ 2016 | Ulsan, South Korea

Nuclear Energy Engineering, B.Sc., Hacettepe University 

2013 | Ankara, Turkey

# **LATEST PROJECTS**

[SMR] Small and Micro Modular Reactors Technology Analyses

[PCCS] Conceptual Design and Development of Passive Containment Cooling System for APR1400

[SMART] System-Integrated Modular Advanced Reactor Passive Containment Cooling System

[PGSFR] Prototype Gen-IV Sodium-Cooled Fast Reactor Condition Analysis

[EUR] APR1000 PAFS Standard Design Development and EUR Certification Support

## **AWARDS & CERTIFICATES**

International Atomic Energy Agency Fellowship, IAEA

Full Academic Scholarship, KINGS

Modeling and Computation of Multiphase Flows, ETH

International Marketing, Business Knowledge and Intelligence, ATO

## PERSONAL VENTURES

Nuclear Industry Association of Turkey, Board of Directors ☑

Turkish Chamber of Commerce in Korea, Co-Founder

Hacettepe Rugby Club, Founder